<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.livespiritlife.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.livespiritlife.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-11T16:42:38+00:00</updated><id>https://www.livespiritlife.com/</id><title type="html">Live Spirit Life</title><subtitle>Your source for mindfullness, health and better living. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meditation Studio App Review</title><link href="https://www.livespiritlife.com/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meditation Studio App Review" /><published>2017-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.livespiritlife.com/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.livespiritlife.com/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review.html">&lt;p&gt;
In our busy lives, mindfulness has become an indispensable option to cope with everyday stress, clarify our cognitive abilities and generally calming our busy minds.

Luckily there are some great (and sometimes free) utilities right at our fingertips. Whether we are just getting started or already an expert, we can get up and running fairly quickly with the use of an app right in our mobile phone.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/meditation_studio_screen1_4-3b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meditation Studio Opening Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
When you first open the app, your experience begins on the Meditations screen which are classified by Collection by default. There is also a handy dropdown to filter the meditations by Collection, Teacher, Duration and Type.  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Once tapping on the selected meditation, the meditation audio will begin to play with the sound of guided, soft spoken words by the meditation guide. There is also a handy option to play Background Sounds if you like, by clicking on the waveform in the upper right. This option is defaulted to None. The guided meditations are of high quality with many different types of meditations available.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/med-app2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meditation Studio Play Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
In Settings, there is another handy option under Audio, to have an Ending Sound of your choice, as the meditations often do not have a clearly defined ending. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the time of this writing there are currently 215 meditations available in the app via Search.  
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In our busy lives, mindfulness has become an indispensable option to cope with everyday stress, clarify our cognitive abilities and generally calming our busy minds.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.livespiritlife.com/assets/images/meditation_studio_screen1_4-3b.png" /></entry></feed>