<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-20T06:49:57-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Live Spirit Life</title><subtitle>Your source for mindfullness, health and better living. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hong-Sau Meditation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/19/hong-sau-meditation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hong-Sau Meditation" /><published>2019-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/19/hong-sau-meditation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/19/hong-sau-meditation.html">&lt;p&gt;
This ancient meditation helps bring calm and focus to your day, and can also be used as precursor to other meditations or exercise. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hong-Sau is Sanskrit for &lt;i&gt;“I am Spirit”&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;“I am He”&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Find a quiet place, face eastward, and sit comfortably with a straight spine (for example Sukhasana). Breath normally and relax.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Close your eyes and focus on the midway point between your eyebrows. From that focused third-eye center, mentally observe the natural ebb and flow like a calm ocean of the body’s breath. Don’t interfere or force the breath in or out, just sit as a detached observer watching the body’s breath go in an out. If it helps with detachment, pretend you are observing another person breathing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As the breath slowly comes into the body, mentally say “Hong” (which rhymes with song), and as the breath exhales out, mentally say Sau (rhymes with saw). Your mouth or tongue should not move, it’s a mental sound. Hear the sound of Hong and Sau literally coming from the breath wind. This ebb and flow should feel natural.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As you begin to feel a deeper calm, feel the breath higher and higher in the nose. If your mind wanders, it’s ok, just bring your attention back to the awareness of the breath and the sound of the words Hong Sau. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Continue to observe the breath and the sounds of the mantra; the repetitions flowing in and out, allow yourself to feel serenity. Continue as you long as you feel comfortable. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This ancient meditation helps bring calm and focus to your day, and can also be used as precursor to other meditations or exercise. Hong-Sau is Sanskrit for “I am Spirit” or “I am He”. Find a quiet place, face eastward, and sit comfortably with a straight spine (for example Sukhasana). Breath normally and relax. Close your eyes and focus on the midway point between your eyebrows. From that focused third-eye center, mentally observe the natural ebb and flow like a calm ocean of the body’s breath. Don’t interfere or force the breath in or out, just sit as a detached observer watching the body’s breath go in an out. If it helps with detachment, pretend you are observing another person breathing. As the breath slowly comes into the body, mentally say “Hong” (which rhymes with song), and as the breath exhales out, mentally say Sau (rhymes with saw). Your mouth or tongue should not move, it’s a mental sound. Hear the sound of Hong and Sau literally coming from the breath wind. This ebb and flow should feel natural. As you begin to feel a deeper calm, feel the breath higher and higher in the nose. If your mind wanders, it’s ok, just bring your attention back to the awareness of the breath and the sound of the words Hong Sau. Continue to observe the breath and the sounds of the mantra; the repetitions flowing in and out, allow yourself to feel serenity. Continue as you long as you feel comfortable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meditation Studio App Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meditation Studio App Review" /><published>2017-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/meditation-studio-ios-app-review.html">&lt;p&gt;
In our busy lives, mindfulness has become an indispensable option to cope with everyday stress, clarify our cognitive abilities and generally calming our busy minds.

Luckily there are some great (and sometimes free) utilities right at our fingertips. Whether we are just getting started or already an expert, we can get up and running fairly quickly with the use of an app right in our mobile phone.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/meditation_studio_screen1_4-3b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meditation Studio Opening Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
When you first open the app, your experience begins on the Meditations screen which are classified by Collection by default. There is also a handy dropdown to filter the meditations by Collection, Teacher, Duration and Type.  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Once tapping on the selected meditation, the meditation audio will begin to play with the sound of guided, soft spoken words by the meditation guide. There is also a handy option to play Background Sounds if you like, by clicking on the waveform in the upper right. This option is defaulted to None. The guided meditations are of high quality with many different types of meditations available.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/med-app2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meditation Studio Play Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
In Settings, there is another handy option under Audio, to have an Ending Sound of your choice, as the meditations often do not have a clearly defined ending. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the time of this writing there are currently 215 meditations available in the app via Search.  
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In our busy lives, mindfulness has become an indispensable option to cope with everyday stress, clarify our cognitive abilities and generally calming our busy minds.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/meditation_studio_screen1_4-3b.png" /></entry></feed>